After you've mastered your round-off, you're able to start moving on into more advanced tumbling.
Now advanced tumbling is most easily done in combination from a round-off because you're going to get a lot of momentum.
Demonstrated right here are the steps that you're going to take in a back handspring.
I highly recommend starting out with spotters.
This is going to be the best way to learn the movements in slow motion, then you can go ahead and take it from there.
Now we can also do all of these tumbles which we're going to call standing format instead of running which is linked onto the round-off.
Now it's important when you're learning your back handspring to have tons of matted floors.
These are going to be provided by your facility when you're tumbling.
Now the correct position to start off with a back hand spring, you're going to want to bend at the knees and rock back on your heels as you take off.
So it's really important, your spotters are going to be behind you, we're going to end up going completely back and landing on the palms of our hands.
Make sure you can keep your arms straight and you want to do a little shrug at the shoulder and then you're going to pop out of it, similarly to how you would pop out of a handstand.
Now it's also important to learn, once you've mastered your back handspring, the second high level skill is going to be your tuck.
Now first you need to master your tuck jump, which is going to be this position here, knees high up on the chest.
And a tuck jump is basically going to be this form with both your knees hugged tightly to your chest in the air.
You can do a running tuck which is going to be attached to your round-off, or your handspring, or you can do a standing still tuck, which is going to be a different prep from our handspring.
We're going to start stationary.
We're going to get up on our toes to get some momentum, and we're going to go straight in.
It's really important to ride your jump up when you're doing a tuck.
You really need to pull yourself all the way to the tippy top before you go into the tuck position.
You want to hold that position tightly until you spin all the way around.
Now a lot of us, when we're landing our tucks, you're going to be in this position down here on the floor a lot when you land your tucks.
That's ok, you're still learning, just get up out of if, and get a spot until you can make that full rotation.
Another tumble which is really advanced is called a layout.
A layout's going to be a flip that's similar to a tuck where your hands never make contact to the ground.
In the air your layout position is basically going to be this.
We're going to do a full rotation in a flat position like this.
After you've mastered your layout, you can start doing fulls which are the most fun tumbling.
A full is going to be a layout in this position with a full rotation in the air.
Those are the most difficult of tumbling passages.
A good way to master those is using trampolines.
You can use foam pits and also definitely use lots of mats.